

sudbasnet.github.io | linkedin.com/in/sudeepbasnet

Address: 5277 W 82nd ST

**Bloomington, MN** 

Phone: 402-617-1329

sudbasnet10@gmail.com Email:

#### **SUMMARY**

Dedicated, career-oriented problem solver with experience in Software & Database Development, and Scientific Research. Interested in Software Development and Database Design. Graduated with a master's degree in Computer Science. Has worked in Agile methodology in Python, C#, TypeScript, R and JavaScript on Windows and Unix platforms.

## **SKILLS**

Python, C#, Typescript, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, R, SQL, NoSQL **Programming:** 

Azure Fundamentals Certification, NodeJS, Angular, Vue, GIT and SVN, Data Analysis, Data Other Technical:

Visualization, Database Development, JIRA, Snowflake DW, MicroStrategy, Markdown

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Technical Consultant -Software Development & Data Warehousing | Oct 2019 - Current

Logic Information Systems, Bloomington, MN

**Software Development** | May 2020 - Current

Developing omni-channel e-commerce solutions with C#, TypeScript, and HTML/CSS in .NET and .NET Core.

#### **Data Warehouse and BI Development** | Oct 2019 - Feb 2020

- Debugged and resolved issues in reporting dashboards, using MicroStrategy Developer, MicroStrategy Architect and MicroStrategy Intelligence Server.
- Designed Cloud Data Warehouse and ETL pipelines in Snowflake along with stored procedures in JavaScript, automated data loading with Python.

### **Graduate Research Assistant** | Jan 2017 - Aug 2019

<u>University of Nebraska – Lincoln (UNL)</u>

- Scientific Data Analysis and data management using Python and R with packages like scipy, scikit-learn, pandas and numpy, utilized parallel computing on Nebraska's second-fastest High-Performance Computing servers.
- Developed a scalable clustering algorithm in Python to perform unsupervised learning on GIS data, with performance gain up to 60% compared to state-of-art algorithms. Published and presented research paper.
- Development and management of PHP backed application with data visualization using HTML/CSS, KnockoutJS, Google Maps JavaScript API and MySQL database. (cse.unl.edu/~surge)
- Developed Agent-based simulation model in *Java* to simulate and predict social unrest on a geographic and temporal scale. (github.com/sudbasnet/SocialUnrestMAS)

#### Data Software Engineer | July 2012 - Dec 2016

Cotiviti Nepal Pvt. Ltd. | Kathmandu, Nepal | (Subsidiary of COTIVITI HEALTHCARE, Waltham MA)

## Software Development - ISP, HTML, CSS | Dec 2015 - Dec 2016

Software Development using Java and Oracle 11g on Windows and UNIX platforms. Involved in Integration, Analysis, Design & Development, Testing and Production support phases.

#### **Data Engineering - Oracle 11g/12g** | July 2012 - Dec 2016

- Implemented Oracle PL/SQL procedures, functions, triggers and packages for data management and statistical report generation. Developed ETL procedures, documented and validated complex rules for data transformation.
- Optimized multiple large clients by 60 70% in processing time using parallel processes, re-designing back-end jobs, performance tuning, normalization and query optimization.

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Computer Science (GPA: 3.8) | Jan 2017 - August 2019

University of Nebraska – Lincoln (UNL)

Relevant Courses: Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Data Structures, Machine Learning, Networking, GIS

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

- CallBreak An Online Multiplayer Card Game using RESTful API (NodeJS, TypeScript, VueJS, WebSockets): github.com/sudbasnet/Callbreak-Frontend-Vue
- Personal website (Angular): <a href="https://github.sudbasnet.io">https://github.sudbasnet.io</a>